Henrik Becker

Software Engineer

+46734228343 www.henrikbecker.net

Summary

A senior full stack developer dedicated to building robust, maintainable and testable systems.

A practitioner of Test Driven Development and agile processes.

An expert in .Net development using C#.

MSCD Web Applications.

Self-educated with 20 years of working experience.

Efficient and a fast learner.

Frameworks

Asp.Net Core Asp.Net MVC Asp.Net Web API Asp.Net Web Forms

React jQuery KnockoutJS WCF

Methods

Continuous Integration Continuous Deployment Test Driven Development Specification by Example Scrum

Certifications

MSCD Web Applications Certified Scrum Master

Languages

Swedish - Native

English - Fluent (IELTS overall score 8.5)

Languages (programming)

C#
JavaScript
TypeScript
CSS
HTML
T-SQL
XML
XSLT

Tools

VB.Net

Azure DevOps
Octopus Deploy
TeamCity
Git
ReSharper
Visual Studio

Databases

SQL Server Azure SQL Database

Project History

Open Payments

2019-12-02 - 2020-06-30, Stockholm, Sweden

Open Payments provides a PSD2-compliant platform letting FinTech, E-commerce businesses etc integrate with European banks through a single unified API - the Open Payments Platform.

Much of my focus lay on implementing automated onboarding in the client's Customer Portal.

A project that involved integration with a variety of Azure resources, Dynamics CRM and KYC/AML services.

Achievements:

- Automated Customer Onboarding
- Test Automation

Technologies used:

- Asp.Net Core
- C#
- React
- Redux
- TypeScript
- Azure
- Azure DevOps
- OData
- Git

Insplanet

2019-01-07 - 2019-06-13, Stockholm, Sweden

The client needed a senior developer with architecture experience to fill in the gap after their architect and lead developer left them.

My role was to make sure that knowledge wasn't lost during the transition so much of the assignment had to do with keeping documentation up to date and accessible.

I also contributed by simplifying their build and deployment processes.

Achievements:

- Zero down time deployment
- Simplified CI process with Azure DevOps build pipelines

Technologies used:

- Asp.Net MVC

- Asp.Net Web Api
- .Net Core
- C#
- React
- TypeScript
- Azure DevOps
- Octopus Deploy

Norconsult Astando

2018-04-18 - 2018-11-30, Stockholm, Sweden

Achievements:

- Automated deployment for the project IsyRoad resulting in:
- Deployment time decreasing from ~ 45 minutes to ~ 5 minutes per application instance
- Deployment releated errors reduced by nearly 100 %

Technologies used:

- Octopus Deploy
- TeamCity
- Asp.Net Web Api
- .Net Core
- WCF
- NHibernate
- C#

Svea Ekonomi AB

2017-10-11 - 2018-04-11, Solna, Sweden

Development of Svea Checkout - an e-commerce payment solution being rolled out in Sweden, Norway and Finland.

Achievements:

- Improved api documentation by generating most of it automatically
- Improved tests by rewriting them as executable specifications

- C#
- Asp.Net Web Api
- CQRS
- Micro Services
- TDD
- Specification By Example
- Continuous Integration

- Octopus Deploy
- NuGet
- Team Foundation Server
- Entity Framework
- DocNet

Plejmo

2014-11-03 - 2017-07-05, Stockholm, Sweden

Back- and front end development of a Video On Demand (VOD) service based on Asp.Net MVC and EpiServer. DevOps tasks including configuring web sites, configuring automated builds and setting up automated deployment.

Achievements:

- Increased system performance by refactoring the system to the CQRS pattern with a denormalized, read optimized database for querying.
- Increased stability and scalability by creating Micro Services for third party integration.
- Reduced errors during deployment by implementing automated deployment.
- Increased code quality by introducing automated acceptance tests and living documentation.

Technologies used:

- Asp.Net MVC 5
- Asp.Net Web Api
- C#
- TDD
- CQRS
- Micro Services
- Continuous Integration
- Application Lifecycle Management
- Octopus Deploy
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Knockout JS
- CSS3
- HTML5
- EPiServer
- NHibernate
- SQL Server
- IIS

Arbetsförmedlingen

2014-06-24 - 2014-09-26, Stockholm, Sweden

Maintenance of a legacy solution for managing requisitions at Sweden's public employment services.

Technologies used:

- VB.Net
- WinForms
- WebForms
- WCF
- WebServices
- Oracle

Qbranch Competence Manager

2014-04-28 - 2014-06-23, Stockholm, Sweden

Development of an application for managing consultant CVs. Built on Asp.Net MVC and hosted on Windows Azure.

Technologies used:

- Asp.Net MVC 5
- HTML5
- jQuery
- CSS3
- C#
- EntityFramework 6
- Test Driven Development
- Continuous Integration

Wasa Kredit

2012-03-12 - 2013-11-14, Stockholm, Sweden

Employed as Lead Developer.

Achievements:

- Reduced complexity and system decay through refactoring and the application of common software architecture patterns.
- Guided the development teams towards an iterative approach to software development with the product owner, functional analysts, testers and developers working closely together during the entire development cycle.
- Introduced the idea of living documentation in the form of executable specifications.

- C#
- WinForms
- Asp.Net MVC4
- HTML

- CSS3
- WCF
- TDD
- BDD
- SpecFlow
- Continuous Integration
- Team Foundation Server- XML
- XSLT

Cale Access AB

2011-09-01 - 2012-03-09, Stockholm, Sweden

Cale is one of the world's leading manufacturers of parking meters.

Henrik was involved in the project "Historical Changes" aiming to facilitate historical changes in "TrueUp". TrueUp is a set of financial rules for economical compensation between the city of Chigago and the company Chicago Parking Meters.

The TrueUp system automates the compensation calculations and is a part of Cale Web Office 2.

Challenges: Complex domain model. Complex business rules. Massive data sets

Technologies used:

- Test Driven Development
- SpecFlow
- NInject
- C#
- WCF
- Asp.Net Web Forms
- Continuous Integration
- Team Foundation Server

CashGuard

2011-06-01 - 2011-09-01, Stockholm, Sweden

CashGuard specialises in cash management solutions for the retail industry.

The software StoreManager is a solution for monitoring of CashGuard systems.

Henrik was the key person in the introduction of behavior driven development (Specification by Example) by taking traditional user stories in Word format and turning them into executable specifications.

Achievements:

- Was the key person in introducing behavior driven development.
- Lay the foundation for automated regression tests and living documentation by taking existing user stories and turning them into executable specifications using SpecFlow.

Technologies used:

- Specification by Example
- SpecFlow
- C#
- WCF
- Asp.Net MVC
- WiX
- SQL Server

Länsförsäkringar

2009-09-01 - 2011-05-01, Stockholm, Sweden

Worked with the development of a WCF based payment platform adding support for automatic payment services and prompts. Quality assurance and performance optimization of connecting systems.

Achievements:

- Was instrumental in the migration of the payment platform's database from Oracle to SQL Server.

Technologies used:

- VB.Net
- WCF
- WPF
- Oracle
- SQL Server
- Team Foundation Server
- Continuous Integration
- Test Driven Development

Tradera

2009-08-01 - 2009-08-31, Stockholm, Sweden

Participated in the development of a sales support system for managing articles and campaigns published on tradera.se.

Technologies used:

- C#
- WCF
- WPF
- NHibernate

Astando

2008-02-28 - 2009-05-01, Stockholm, Sweden

Astando is one of the leading companies in the GIS area and in the forefront of the Local Roaddatabase concept (LV).

LV is the foundation on top of which applications concerning the road network, traffic and road-users are built. The assignment involved development of a client/server application for importing and presenting traffic measurement data for Stockholm and Gothenburg.

Technologies used:

- C#
- Winforms
- Windows Services
- Oracle
- NHibernate
- Spring.Net
- Test Driven Development
- Continuous Integration

hitta.se

2006-03-01 - 2008-02-28, Stockholm, Sweden

Hitta.se is a Swedish search engine that offers telephone directory, addresses and maps. It has been one of Sweden's 10 most popular sites for quite some time, I worked with hitta.se's internal order system and improved the public map site with services such as weather and traffic information.

Achievements:

- Was a key person in the development of hitta.se one of Swedens top 10 most popular sites.
- Created the services hitta.se/trafiknytt (traffic information) and hitta.se/vader (weather information).

Technologies used:

- C#
- Asp.Net
- AJAX
- T-SQL
- MSMQ
- XML
- XSLT
- XHTML
- SQL Server
- IIS

ICA Banken AB

2006-03-01 - 2006-03-01, Sundbyberg, Sweden

Quality analysis of database design. Trouble shooting and optimization of SQL scripts for data import/export and

database maintenance. VBScript for SQL Server inventory using WMI.

Technologies used:

- SQL Server
- T-SQL
- VBScript
- XML
- XSLT
- WMI

Sigtuna Council

2005-10-01 - 2006-03-01, Märsta, Sweden

Was the single developer on this Identity Management project that would become Microsoft's reference case for Microsoft Identity Integration Server (MIIS).

Implemented management agents for the client's HR system, the directory services eDirectory and Active Directory.

Implemented automatic creation of GroupWise accounts and Novell Server home directories.

Wrote rules extensions for attribute flow and joins.

Technologies used:

- Identity Management
- Microsoft Identity Integration Server
- C#
- SQL Server
- Novell eDirectory
- Active Directory
- MSMQ
- Novell C API
- GroupWise Administrative Objects API

Sveriges Television

2005-07-01 - 2005-07-31, Stockholm, Sweden

Maintenance of the client's system inventory tool.

- VBScript
- VBA
- T-SQL
- SQL Server
- ASP

Taxi Stockholm

2005-05-01 - 2005-07-01, Stockholm, Sweden

Migration of Taxi Stockholm's intranet and external web site from Spirello to EpiServer. Integration with the client's Unix based booking system.

Technologies used:

- Asp.Net
- C#
- EPiServer 4
- SQL Server

Siemens Medical

2000-01-01 - 2001-01-01, Stockholm, Sweden

QA and supporting colleges during development and maintenance of Siemens Medical's intranet "EMPower".

Technologies used:

- Visual Basic 6
- COM
- ASP
- JavaScript
- XML
- XSLT
- CSS
- HTML
- SQL Server

Hewlett Packard Sweden

1999-09-01 - 2005-03-31, Solna, Sweden

Requirements analysis, use case design, system design and development of a web based admininstration interface for information about and registrations for customer events for HP EMEA.

Requirements analysis, design and development of a web based administration interface for HP's scandinavian products database.

Development of templates for the client's EpiServer based intranet.

Maintenance and further development of www.hp.se.

- C#
- Asp.Net
- T-SQL

- SQL Server
- IIS
- EPiServer
- XML
- XSLT
- ASP
- JavaScript
- VBScript
- HTML
- CSS

Looström & Gelin AB

1998-10-01 - 1999-07-31, Danderyd, Sweden

Designed and developed a document management system based on Visual Basic 5. Assisted in developing the company web site.

- Visual Basic 5
- COM
- ASP

Employment History

2015-09 - 2017-07 Plejmo Backend Developer at Magine TV 2014-11 - 2015-08 Plejmo Backend Developer at Film2Home AB
2014-04 - 2014-09 IT Consultant/Technical Manager at Qbranch Stockholm AB
2012-03 - 2013-11 Lead Developer at Wasa Kredit AB
2008-01 - 2012-03 IT Consultant/System Developer at Avega Group AB
2007-12 - 2008-01 System Developer at Aftonbladet Tillväxtteknik 2 AB
2007-04 - 2007-12 IT Consultant/System Developer at Inverso International AB
2005-04 - 2007-04 IT Consultant/System Developer at Qbranch Stockholm AB
2002-01 - 2005-03 IT Consultant/System Developer at eWork
1999-09 - 2002-01 IT Consultant/System Developer at IconMedialab AB
1998-10 - 1999-07 Programmer at Innitek AB
1997-07 - 1998-10 PC Technician at Lidingö Stad
1986-12 - 1995-06 Shop Assistant at Konsumentföreningen Stockholm
1994-01 - 1994-07 Study Circle Leader at Sollentuna Jazz Workshop
1992-06 - 1992-09 Shop Assistant at Kantarellen Livs AB
1986-08 - 1986-12 Shop Assistant at Karena Zoo, Lek & Hobby

Education

1995 - 1997 KomVux Lidingö1992 - 1993 Kulturama